Hi, good afternoon everyone and welcome welcome to the session and my name is bill
gibsonI'm a program manager...the as...sequel database group.
And,my colleague...drops I'm also program manager on the other
...database t and then I have been partners in crime for the last couple of weeks
preparing this sessionwhich has been a lot of fun so we're looking forward to sharing that with
...we've got lots of things to talk about so let's dive in the first of all we have to
Just remind...that evaluations...important
...we'd love to get your feedback on the session itself so please go ahead and do that?
So, let's just quickly survey we're going to talk about this afternoon jam-packed session
...going pretty quickly so I can do a very quick sort of forty thousand foot look,
at as a...database kind of hoping most of you familiar with the service...shouldn't we
...be dueling much on the general features of it I'm going to talk particular about the topic of the day
...which is building sas applications and how
a characteristics of the database platform a particularly suited to that task
about application spaceparticularly ...talking about the way we can a
...you particularly now with new things we're doing with developing a managing large
...databases which is a characteristic of course of
sas applications and then handling unpredictable workloads and that's a key
theme...keep touching on several times during the session and
...unpredictability that comes from not knowing who your customers
are your the end-user and quite what the workloads of those people are so
let's dive in as a...database then this is my forty thousand foot view
of this so it's a global fully manage databases a service
...paz model for databases you just gotta buy and
consume databases create them as you want when you want we think it's think of it is being
...for sas and enterprise applications...it's built to scale
...to handle a wide range of workloads and we'll be talking about that
as we go and a key thing that we've introduced and
if you listen to the keynote yesterday you would have heard about the elastic database model and we're going
to be talking about that today particularly focusing on that?
And, as a service it has...unprecedented availability for
nines availability across the globe in seventeen regions across the globe and
we have tremendous a...we have replication model and
this a local replication model but also in case of disaster recovery scenarios we
have geographic replication between those regions and the
ability to restore the databases should that should...be a disaster at anyone region
so it's important characteristic that of an enterprise class service.
And, the databases themselves a secure that protected and that compliant with
a wide range of international standards so
we've spent a lot of effort making sure this is a platform that you can trust and
build solid applications on and significantly we've been
...towards this place but now with release
of full-text search of this happen now and preview and we can now claim that
we're fully compatible with sequel server twenty fourteen databases so
that database level compatibility so effectively sequel that you
can write to run on premises you can now run the clouds as a tremendous,
tremendous compatibility that so that's great story helping customers with migration scenarios,
for example.
And, throughout the evolution of the
platform of the service we focus heavily oneasy development and
easy self-service management so the...that you can take over the service
you can manager grafting yourself...been a key characteristic of that.
And, you'll see great evidence of that and in the experiences will show you this afternoon.
And, then if we think about the way we deliver a service to-you we deliver it in these service
...we use we have to is for basic standard and premium
databases so you can buy databases and any one of those tails and
they differ they differ in terms of the target intend so their intended
use here basic for like transactional loads standard we think of go to
the...full terrified for the most business application workloads
...target into that space and then premium for our
high and high throughput business critical applications so you can see that one of the key things
the difference between those two is the performance
and we'll talk much more about maps we go through so the basic databases have
effectively that the lowest-level performance so,
they have a price that's corresponds.
Then standard...premium we offer increasing levels of performance...
hoods but perhaps what's most interesting about this image is not what's different about the
services but what's the same about them so significantly the and,
relevant to the talk today we have this
...model of workload elasticity...the fact we can create databases that
...different levels but also we can create databases and what
...we've introduced now the elastic database pools and these and,
we'll be talking about these pools allow database to flex and to show great dynamics
...you will to changes...workload...rapidly so
let's very new concept...and significant significantly
where allowing enabling this across all these...
The compatibility and the high availability I
mention again the same across all these two is, you know,
sacrificing any of those features so on of philosophy is very much now
that you can build an application once and then skated as you need across these different
up service here offerings and elasticity of frames.
So, let's give you a taste we're...take a look quickly at a.
A demo application
that we've built and that's going to show some of the characteristics of a
...application so we switch over to this so this isan application and
...in the as session earlier today which was a
wing tip tickets session I have to be say that very carefully but,
I probably will fail several times and?
So, we took that application which is designed
as a global service and we've turned into a sas applications so we've turned
into an application which can be used by different customers so think of
asses the sas provider we sell it to different companies who are interested in organizations
in selling tickets so here we've got a jazz club might be a small
company that is selling tickets to the customers on another one here
...and we've got contest so
concert hall and just if we look down for
...is this is real application I can move around here and,
significantly the data for each of these customers is completely separate that's, you know,
...a key characteristic of us...each customer buying this application
buying this service application as a service from the...once their data
to be private and we can open up another one of these and.
Again,...of assigned before some isa judo school that's
also selling tickets...tournaments that they posts
...school here and, you know, I can come in and I can buy tickets here
and you just sort of actually I need...sign in first-floor I can do that so let me
...just think about what I'm doing I'm signing in here.
As a as a user of the dog would doj I'm not a...of when tips wing
tip tickets global service and...not like ticketmaster something like that this is
I'm a private custom...private end-user of this particular
...judo schools application they value may as a customer they
what my email address that able to share with anybody else they want to sell me tickets that a
one meet wandering off into some other site and,
doing something else buying tickets or some other event so it's a private experience the
customize for me the use a customized by it the customer
of the wing tip tickets platform
the science provider right so I can come in here and I could go ahead and,
buy tickets you can see that experience here I'm
...go ahead we don't need to do on that one but...I've done
...back to the other is basically motivate some qualities than
...are important about this...the next.
And, about...I describers data intensive sas applications so there are
sas applications...not so data intensive it wouldn't be so rather
than what we're talking about the ones that are is
that whisky notion data isolation and privacy and protection in the
other one any anyone breaking out of one
customer space customer data spaces somehow seeing the data from somewhere else
and there's this notion of scale because a sas provide I want to be able to scale
...support unlimited customers...start today with only ten or twenty customers and maybe I
just have one customer but I want to design and applications going to scale?
So, that's the key quality that I...want and then we're going to come back to this idea
of unpredictable usage so the dog would though...and the composer concept
...radically different size customers with potentially very different usage patterns in
...one has frequent concerts...one has occasional tournaments same sort of requirement
but very different profiles of usage.
Traditionally...say that...sort of you know, there's a common...of building
sas applications multi customer database applications is to is to
use a...database strategy to put
have allows database and put all the customer data into that one database and
key it in some way on the customer id so that you
oil queries now carefully extract the right customers data from the database unless
an effective model and it certainly one that's ...work for many people but the obviously
...a kind of complicated designers shopping
...design because you're still going to run out of space and even the largest databases
...introduces...management complexity...happens if a customer
...error you have to go and pick one customs data app data out of that
...database and recover it took some earlier point in time it's a complex problem because solve?
So, why not do a different way why not build each customer each customer
database so now instead of having twenty two hundred two thousand twenty
thousand customers and jammed into a small number database want to
...them all...one reaction to that in the past has
...an awful lot of databases to manage and, the vast the point that we're really addressing
with changing the way you can think about managing large numbers of databases...but if you can go with
...just sort of sustain that for from moment that we...solve these problems
...database management then and...at this...the, you know, look,
at the things that the platform brings you because we sell
you individual databases we focus all our attention on managing databases not
managing customers inside the database so now managing a database you give one
customer database is effectively managing the customers if I can monitor and
secure an audit interactions with a single database I'm watching what that
customers doing in that database as customers come and go as
customers needs capacity needs change those
...there's a equate to the lifecycle of an individual database
...database when I need one if the dates a customer goes...I can take it out of
circulation funny to skated up I can skated up so on again this
...recovery I can recover an individual database now very easy
...very fast because anyone...data is typically small so I can recover
...earlier point in time some of...cool thing about this...development
standpoint is the schemas unchanged by this so it doesn't matter how many
customers you have you just...the schema for a single customer and,
that other parts of the system...scale?
So, I talked...providing tools like a into.
A system this process so things we're doing now adding to the
sort of copy of tool obviously we've got a management tools in the form of the as your portal,
for example, but, also we're adding
the facility for across database query for reporting analytics and,
data integration on you to move data between databases so,
now you better run a query across a large...databases we'll see that in a moment
also running jobs across large numbers of databases
and then you can connect with the traditional set of tools
...no difference here these are especially now that we've ...
the database compatibility with sequel server twenty fourteen all
of the tools you're familiar with a programming experience is database programming...you familiar
with all apply now to these databases there's nothing special I just individual databases.
Okay, so, we take a look at the application the architecture
...wing tip tickets the sas application this is the architecture we've
implemented...really is what we've built here so, it's a cloud service
...you connect to it through the customer specific endpoints and
then we use system to grouchy to the correct database based on
the customer identity's was you identify yourself you come in herewe do that routing
in fact that's the first of several challenges that we're going to talk to is we...through here so I'm...tossed and,
...you pick it up have thank you bill.
So, basically looking at this picture one of the first
challenges you're probably going to realize soon as a customer connects to
...endpoint we've chosen traffic manager to implement these and points
...different urls but you could choose different approaches as well
imagine a customer and their end-users are starting to use
...that endpoint...have...to the requests are coming into our cloud
service we need to find out what's the corresponding database...data...that we need to
...docked...too and we need to broker the
appropriate connection the way that we do that...we basically keep the mapping information that maps
...request a come...through the url to
...school corresponding databases we copy store that in...database
...them and how we're actually doing that and based on that then we have the information
...allows us to get the connection into the right database for that
tenant?
that's kind of the first challenge that we have to deal with it most or if not all
...providers on how to deal with whether using multiple databases and,
you can obviously go ahead and brides all that code yourself ...basically
...the mapping store keep track of all of the databases that a participate in your
...you could implement that yourself however,
we are providing you a lot of help with the elastic database tools
...a set of libraries that specifically targeted odp this
problemthe first one is basically having a data to your that comprises
many databases how do I define dot a set or group of databases and,
then how do I store how customers or tenants rb
knocked maps to individual databases so that's the multi database management aspect
...covering with the libraries in a lasting database tools the second aspect
then goes back to the challenges edit just described using the information about
...different databases and the mapping of customers to databases how
do you efficiently broker connections for incoming requests to the right databases and
that's another key aspect in those libraries and ...I want
to cloud specifically as you can imagine that every incoming request does a round-trip into the
catalog database to...find the
mopping that can at some point become very efficiently database...the can become a
bottlenecks so we havea lot of attention to make sure that we have a very effective caching scheme
and place so that you are most cases award...actual round-trip institute into the
catalog database and that's also included as part of the libraries
and we're very excited this week to
...we have made these libraries generally available and behold that gives you a lot
of confidence using these libraries for your applications
...fairly approachable fairly easy to find so if you go into no,
good in visual studio and the package manager and search for elastic scale you'll
find them immediately and it's basically set of kline libraries...new...that you can download there?
So, what I want to do next is basically walk you through an example of scaling out the data to
your of our application by adding a new demo customer into the mix and,
then illustrating how all this data depended routing that connection brokering works
through through our elastic database tool libraries so let's go ahead with that?
Just a second.
To switch over.
Okay, so, what I've done is I've put together a...shell script?
Basically abstracts the most important steps and, the first one is
...just parameters so we're going to create a new customer that's called demo concert hall.
On the database
...is going-to be a provision on this survey here...our
catalog database this is the actual cloud service url as you're behind it and,
then...a bunch of credentials let me put that in real quick.
And, then you see the rest of the step's going to walk
to the is the first one is the one that's going to take a little bit longer and,
especially calling another partial scripted takes care of creating the ...the underlying database
for the customer and as your sequel db on that server that we have seen
will also take initial steps to populate that database with the schema that
...expecting our customers or tendons to have and
...application so that's also abstracted behind this call them
...here all of this using standard partial interfaces to address
...to create...database in the first-place but also...to run the sequel statements
...that newly created database that provisions the schema provisions the table
for our application and while we're waiting for that database to
get created from the next step that you already see here and there...finished so
we have a new database the next step is basically taking that database and registering
at in the customer catalog as a new customer as a new database that
a soon incoming requests can get routed to so let's run this statement as well.
And, that behind-the-scenes uses partial dot net integration to call into
our elastic scale libraries to add the new database into that what we call the
shark map the catalog and also register the mapping all the new tenant and
it's id to the database...just provisions let's put in some.
Right.
And, the last step is let's put a url through traffic manager on top of that.
You see...demo concert hall.
...wtwo peed...traffic manager net provisions for us.
So, without everything should be...place sasha better use...yeah,
let me first go into visual studio here and connect to the debug
rtwo are running cloud services hang on for a second.
So, here is the cloud service that's implementing...application.
...attached debug ahead.
Ok, let's wait for the symbols to load.
you see asset...break point in an interesting place let's switch over to bill.
For just a minute...guess what I'm going to do is basically connect to that customer
...type in the urls...simple scheme here we use the name of the customers the name of
...database the namely url so I'm going-to go ahead and connective that so, that's me
sending off the requests and you see the request hangs for an obvious reason we
had to break point in the debug are...statement here and now let
me explain what's actually happening with this statement so I have a class or name space
as charting has a static class basically singleton for the mapping
and the customer catalog and that's this customer shark map that I'm hovering over right now and,
that is using our elastic database libraries and the libraries
expose a call that is called open connection for key which
returns a regular ado dot net sequel connection but it uses the
...id or the customer identity if you want as
an input parameter to identify what is the correct database that this connection should get
...and all dot is done basically on the information
that you half provided about the mappings of your customers to the underline databases that
stored...abstracted behind that customer shark map object that you see here and,
then as we execute this
...open a regular sequel connection you see from that point on it's just regular eighty dot net
sequel, sequel coming onto switch back to me and...run this
...real quick and...we should save this guy should now return.
Survivor.
And, we have so what we've got actually is a customized experience...for
...customer obviously the...as a customer of I just
if I...to wing tip tickets and tossed
...done this provisioning job my problem...will be about...that's not going customize this cisco
...events and...so this is what I'm saying the experience for a
new customer so that's why it's different from the experience that
an existing customize so that's the that's the routing story
and what this cool if you think about it is all the magic happened...one statement that was one-line you
and inject into your application there instead of creating
a normal connection you create this connection through the magic of this ...system that
...fairly mechanical change so if you have and existing application existing piece of code
just calls regular...connection constructor and open call on the connection it's
really easy to change that code and use a new libraries?
Okay, so, that was that was a demo there so the next challenge
...talk about is this notion of predictable performance levels so I talked about they.
The case of different size companies the dog would...small geo school compared to the
...a concert whole perhaps compared to other companies...different sizes and
this kind of sense that I can predict that there are can be a busy app is.
The...will be busy ad they'll be more ticket purchases that cilantro concert hole they have more
come concerts than the dough has judo events so I consider
predict that I want to have different performance levels so there's a certain
amount of predictability as a set amount especially when you're starting out where
you can get the hang of what's going on and you can manage this
so let's talk about performance here I've got the idea that there's the arrows sizes that
reflect the some volume of workload coming in to each of those the different customers
...customer databases but before we can talk about performance and...to share kind
of concept with the and share the way we think about performance...on databases in the
...so we introduce this notion of a database throughput unit think
...for databases how...you kind of
put behind a database and this unit it's actually
a measure of relative measure performance on for dimensions so these
for dimensions here that of the amount of memory the amount of
write io log ios amount of compute cpu our and then the amount of
...capacity that we...read io capacity?
And, it's a relative measure we don't publish absolute numbers for these because
we as a platform provider ourselves reserve the right to adjust the hardware just
the performance and frankly to upgrade the specification of
our service of the time so this isn't
but we do is publish this is a relative measure to help you understand the
...performance of different levels in the service if we look at
anyone database and we can think of well how much of
that as a use here so we can think of a du meter here so I have a
database chugging along a using some amount of that then I might have a workload
that extends uses more of the memory than the other dimensions
there and you can see that we measure the du consume the database throughput units
...consumption...the largest of a dimensions at any moment in time the so in
terms of what is...you're using most of the moment that is your sort of us they think of...the
...this moment so we change the size of this you can see that
...is...access but out the same amounts
...still twenty this...grown overall so we think of this is xxx
...and this guy is kind of gone off to the side here
...further out so that's forty...so this perhaps is a boxes
...that...use and that's the point the box represents a
...of capacity were offering to your database so you provision
...database and can assigned to it amount of capacity so we look at the
this sort of notion of predictable performance levels you can see that we have I
...the scaling performance course basic
standard premium we have this range of performance levels of pricing
tiers they correspond to a and if we just sort of what to database I can
...database
up through any one of these often down I can so as I predict the
need or I see the need for more performance I can make I can
scala database to accommodate that so if I see that a particular one-pass
...being told...a by a custom ...like to have more performance
...possibly...some top offices coming to some small jazz cub to
plan unplug session I can anticipate more demand
and give that database...capacity and I can do that
in a sort of predictable way so how do how do we do that well
there this is actually not use...demo this we talk more about the elastic
...a second but I've got if I use the portal I've got a range these a pricing
cards which basically ramnik pick the different performance levels or I can do this
encode I can use a tci equal I can connect to the master database
an issue a query...can modify the addition here and I can do the same through our
shell as partial script for doing this and we have...api
and deed the all of these mechanisms the portal on these of t
sequel in the partial all end up calling the same apis
there's no difference in the behavior you issue t sql we pick that up unwrapped backs
...management service and the operate on the database in the same way so as a range of
apis a range of partial a features...managing scaling which is?
...my database going to be...there is indeed has great straight
...great question so that scaling couple things about the scaling action.
And, is that ...my game by...they
...at the scaling action the database stays online throughout this the change the
changes typically...instantaneous that can be some period of...so
...is why we say you should think about predictingperformance needs and, skating them
...of that so if we look here what this means we can think about scaling
the databases than to support the different loads on each database okay so that was kind of
easy enough...small was...company I can maybe manage a small
number databases that way but you can see how that would get increasingly complicated
to try and predicts the workload needs of...okay for maybe twenty
...maybe a hundred customers that gets to be a bit more problematic if you've got
thousands of customers and we have got systems you can write scripts and use
our apis to write controlling software that would, for example,
detect workload changes and would scale for you so you can take these actions because the
whole services programmable so you can kind of accommodate that but you go to work kind of
...dash problem so what about a
different way of solving this when we've got hundreds or thousands of
databases so this is where we introduce the elastic database model so
...database model introduces the idea of elastic databases and elastic database
pool so these this is the notion of providing a pool of resources that can be shared
among many databases particular appropriate for databases anal active
...time and people on buying concerts every buying tickets to concerts every second of
every day may have bursts of activity but that, you know, the database is
not going to be used...time by all those customers so we've got all sorts of a
opportunity time slice the interactions to basically
share the resources instead of giving each customer resources and with
the danger of over provisioning for some all under provisioning others and basically not be able to bounce
...costs as the...provider whatever I can
do a better job of predicting the used in aggregate of a set of databases so that's
what the...database model is all about so we're introducing our where it
...goes into public preview this at this conference we announced it and
is now available for use ...indeed we're using it in and indeed
...demo application is running against a pool of databases
you've seen here and we have started with in the
previews just the standard a lasting database and the standard elastic database
pools that is the...that corresponds to the range
of performance available to a standard ordinary...database so
it ranges between tend to use in a hundred dts?
So, that's what's available we have a pool then with a
...sizes ranging between two hundred and twelve hundred to use so you can put a large number databases in
the currently have a limit of a hundred databases but these are just sort of
like getting started limits we put in place we will have
smaller pools and much larger pools and they'll be more
pool sizes in-between photo scaling the pool itself...a more
...granularity fashion and again you can create and configure...through various means a through
...rest apis and for the portland I'll show you that just a second and then you can
move databases...out again databases remain online...the moving them in
...cel between pools and then we've got monitoring
...alerting...facilities so you can in the same way today you can monitor
alert the performance be alerted on changes to the performance of
an individual database you cannot get the same experience across the pool itself so that's got
to take ...for that just illustrate a couple of points here one
is the idea of the database...so I mentioned
the pool itself supports databases a standard...supports the same
...performance as a...anda standard database so
...from ten through one hundred to use so
...where you've got a burst level as a...so these
boxes now represent each boxes scale to be the height of the
pool two hundred four hundred eight hundred twelve hundred which of the initial
...size offerings then you can see how
...individual databases aren't going to get to burst all way up to twelve hundred to use but they get to
pers of this standard level but what can I do this is I can now put into
this large number databases you can see quite clearly I could put many more databases into a
larger pool and that's the key of this is having support for large numbers of
databases we hope to dramatically growth by potentially orders of magnitude the
size of pools that we support the so...the space on that one so from
our architecture standpoint what does this mean.
Means we can put databases into pools we can group them together...give them shared
resources...can be a different sizes different types I can give different
...characteristics of different databases in each
of those pools and I can now support in this way I can scale out
the to support the performance requirements of a large number databases
...critical here is this bursting ability between effectively zero and one
hundred to use is now available to every single database so I haven't got to worry about scaling the databases up
and down between somewhere between a and zero and sone and stwo
...sthree I just say...in the pool and now they get...scale up and down I've got more efficient
du usage because
each databases in active isn't using the database of his capacity that
might have been reserved for that is now available for other databases to use and I've got this
bursting ability ok so let's takea look at this.
So,...I'm in the portal...to do...this demonstration the portal
because the portal is just a great way especially when you're handling large numbers of databases
it's a great way...switch from managing many databases to managing a few a number of
pool's is a great place that you bail to operate on the so here's
a server which has got a associated with a set of databases
...see here these are the databases that correspond to the differentclubs and...
Sign up for a service so I'm going-to go ahead and...so I'm doing this I
said the services running into a pool already it is under got another,
another...set up with the same...show you how...creation works so let's just do
that so I'm and purses adding a pool...if it's a preview as I
have to accept the terms that's been done already we only support one to the moment this the standard
here so I'm going-to go ahead and add the databases we using ...which is going to actually
analyze the set of databases and analyze they usage profile...pool to be
compose of appropriately size databases so databases
...that are bursting beyond...currently active beyond the level of
...to use wouldn't be good candidates because they would be capped
norwood databases and, that have a sort of constant usage profiles
...databases being hammered over time that wouldn't be a good canada put into a pool, you know,
you want to use databases that are being the have
...kind of usage profile so let's go ahead and select the ones that
...and it's actually recommended every database in our in architecture here and
all customer service because that's the characteristic of...workload that is the infrequently
uses I've been saying and it's also recommended a pool size which ashes...to...
The full-size here.
And, for the first-time in weeks.
So, what you maybe just...this and if we can
...artist we have title databases samoa?
Right so rather sadly one of our
graphs hasn't shown up of describe what you would have seen so, we have to basically scales
here to adjustments we can make to a...we can change the size of the pool so I can
scala database here up and down the pool size up and down it's
...scaling the access the as I hit these higher levels and,
I can adjust the amount of that capacity given to each database so we use the same
amount for every database here...and currently a set of one hundred
but you can see we've got scale here is the...and average...to use that
have been analyzed over the last fifteen to thirty days of the databases that
we're thinking of putting into this pool and it's basically showing me how much
...in the to-you...how many did use they've been using so it's looking at historical
performance and saying okay so if I if I were to,
for example, reduce the bursting from a hundred down
to fifty you can see we would actually cap some of those databases they would some of that
...would now not be allowed...not be allowed I mean they would
...down that's what...would nothing would be terminated that we know connection
...just slow down the performance to that so that level so we probably what a
key point...though is to think about what is it that's going on you may be happy to have
some best important queries capped for the sake of allowing more databases to
have more capacity to burst more free obviously database that bus...is
using a capacity that is now available wafts...for other databases
second of tuning measure that you've got that shooting option you can also set a minimum go
back to a hundred here...minimum du this will be actually reserving the to
use reserving capacity for databases as soon as you start doing that you effectively
start and decreasing the number databases...allowed so...if I have that
zeroed we actually have...now system limit of one hundred databases pool you can see
...up...ten that limit comes down to twenty
that's very simple is the two hundred to use divided by ten...
guarantee everyone every database and get...gus you can only have twenty database
and apple so this is an option it's not one we think will be used by many people very
...people going to have a profile...says
the suggests they wanna-be of just allow the databases come and go...use zeroed have
...reserve them when they're not active but it depends entirely on you
...requirements so then I could go ahead andexcept that
let me tell you what you didn't say.
That you will see when you use the services in this...space here we actually
plot on the aggregate usage of the aggregate storage of databases in the
pool you're proposing to put into the pool so we actually aggregate basically we're
looking to see if we would have won the databases you've picked...have been in the pool for
the last month how much capacity with a of the and
the what you would have seen is a...a growing trend line of storage space
here indicating that we will two hundred to use as well size he was a good recommendation and you
...see that if you scale it up to four hundred you would have had masses of head room so this is a good way
...to choose the size of pool...of...you want to have.
See go ahead and select and we would select okay here...back to the stop or
...it will put up the asti pool here so I can now ...create a...unless
...created the...start moving the databases into the pool each database remains with
...current service term pricey and...until it lands in the pool...it subject to
the performance of the pool ok now like any good...show I have one of these.
Creative already so we take a quick look at the...using for the demo itself.
Well, this leads.
So, we've got the same graf information
here about the historical performance so these are the same databases running the same test
...again so we see the same performance profile and what this is telling me here?
And,...oa data that's the that's the kind of shape...seen so we are running a
workload against these databases we open up and see that's the databases.
...and open any one of these here we can open and see the individual workloads we running
attest workload against...that actually have people buying tickets for
often tissues and you can see that there's a...
periodic basically it comes in we buy a bunch of tickets and we go off and these databases
...different timed kind of pattern here...this going on and,
you can see here we've got the graf then showing us and we've
seen a similar graph and the in the earlier display showing the anticipated
utilization and in the way that you could set this up.
Beforehand we can come in here and we can scale now the same
the same qualities we can set scale the size of the pool and we can scale the
maxima minimum...database to optimize the pool...current workload
also from here you can we go back to this databases lists you can add and
remove databases from the pool from here so you can go and add database to the pool
...on the server but not yet in the pool.
Okay,
so, in...time ...of skip the that last piece that's going
and ...to moi.
Okay.
So, the that we talk about handling sort of.
This unpredictable workload sense of it
...unpredictability then matches well to the notion of this elastic pool but
...and then we have that we have and even with a pool
for a particulate intense workloads how we handle that of course the to models
...the notion of elastic databases...normal databases with
...individually scale performance so what we can do is if we if we now
predictable see that as a intends workload requirement we can take database
pool we can skated up its can survive in this...can stay as long as
a likes in this state of being outside the pool of having the being
assigned the performance that it needs to get the job done and as that workload
kind of quite asses on...and we see that we don't need that are perhaps this was the this was the
unplugged concept of the...here and,
then we can bring it back down to size and drop it in fact you can drop it straight back into the pool and it will it
will now adjusts itself to the characteristics of a pool let's actually.
Go on talk about this guy.
you see now you can put...of databases in the pool now we can very effectively manage
there are performance characteristics to capacity...resources as a
sas provider lots of databases the next obvious challenge
you'll run into is a
...across that set of databases in your data
...so imagine you have tens or hundreds of databases how complicated
would be to manage different connection strains individually to
...open up the connections programmatic leo throughthrough a script and,
then putting all the results together in one place
so you to address these challenges we announced earlier in the
keynote on wednesday ...database queries which gives you the ability to
connect into a single...db database and register
and underlying said of databases the customer databases in this picture here register
...a set of databases that you can query through a single
sequel statement from a single database connection and
...illustrating thissingle database as the elastic
...database that's living off to the left off the customer databases
...since it's a single and just regular sequel server database you can use all
...familiar tools and programming paradigms to connect to the
odp elastic database query database and then
you sequel to transparently query across
your data your with tens hundreds or maybe even thousands of databases so?
Let me tell you a little bit more about this I mentioned a lot of the these points
or even talking to the previous slide one key aspect to keep in mind and we'll see that in the demo
...just a minute is that...leverages dee the capabilities that we saw in the first
...that I showed where you are using the elastic database tools
to libraries to store the set of databases and to keep the
mappings of tenants and customers to these different databases so
...database query leverages out information that be stored in
that customer catalog databases leverages dot and can then and
...virtue of doing that knows what's the set of databases
that queries should stretch over it's a very straightforward simple experiencethe setup is
basically just two different new dl statements that were introducing into
t sequel and from that point on
...just regular to...queries against what looks like
tables but essentially a view over databases that are physically...and,
scale out across your data to you so let me show you that in action?
...back into visual studio.
And, what you see here is let me start first illustrating the dl statements that you would needs
to run and I've done that on the databases we're connected to on the elastic query
database I've already done that previously the first one is the creation of what we call
...external data source and it's parameters
...basically taking the information about the customer
catalog and the metadata that
the libraries use to do the connection brokering for us analysis that is
essential what you see here and, there's a view that we can use?
The results and we have one that has been pre provision
...this guy down here we've given it a name.
And, that's our external data source.
And, we're using that then in the statements that you see here
...are creating external tables and these external tables of the look and
behave like regular tables but they don't hold actual data physically in the database
...created...basically just a shell on top of the data that's living physically
distributed in the databases and the underlying data...and they know about these databases
...dot external data source if we just created in the previous allstate and
what I've done in this example here's I've created rone table customer configuration
as one of the tables in the...data...here's a second one country?
And,...this let me run a few simple queries on top of that here's
one example going against the external table customer configuration and let's run this
...takes a second and what the queries basically doing it's showing for us the styles
of themes and...of the sas application of chosen for their websites
...make this a little bit larger so you see that we have a lot of fans of
jackass and a lot of
theater fans as well so that's kind of the distribution information that we can
paul very easily and that can be very important information from the as ask provided to see what's the behavior
of my customer what are the interests and,...can do that with just a simple single
...statement here is very similar information about what
countries we're supporting for our customers in that sas application right now we
are very limited in I just supporting the united states will this change that and yeah,
that's...we can fix and we're both not from the states?
So, that basically gives you a quick view into elastic database
curry's that key take aways are...into a single database...using regular t
...but essentially happens for you behind-the-scenes...the query runs across tens or
hundreds of databases and address equal...doing the heavy lifting for you for...
distant distributed processing that needs to happen for that now we talk about queries and obviously
the focus will queries as an interactive scenario I come in with the t sql query they want
to run right away or I'm using a report you can use...connects to the elastic
query database two-run reports there's another scenario there's a little different that's typically in
a batch context with...administrative tasks or operational task imagine that in the
lifecycle of your application on every...provides going to hit that as the walls
their application over time you have to make schema changes or you have to
roll-out additional reference data provision new user...or rotate, rotate the
administrator password so the challenge of your facing as there's a piece of t sequel that
I need to run against each and every database in my pool or in the set of customer data
basis for my application and what we also showed as part of the keynote
and that we started in preview this week is what we call elastic database jobs
it capability that allows you to submit at
...statement against the pool...database pool and have address equally
...take care of running dot statement across ...set of databases and,
you could think of hey I can do thiswith the for each of loop in
...as well as their couple of
...additional capabilities...you get withelastic database jobs so for instance if you're
...failures for some of the databases along the way as you roll-out
...sequel statement
...database jobs will automatically retry your to
...scripts against those databases in the presence off transient failures and,
let me show you this
...action in the demo?
...switch over.
I didn't go to the...so...didn't see the nice lights without that's too bad so.
...of coming out on that are also well-behaved so.
Let me ...the portal here is.
The elastic...that we are using for
...and up here.
You see the experience to create jobs and.
Let's
create a job like this to role reference data.
And, here you see.
...fixing the problem that...limited to the united states...
...from the uk...germany's elise add those countries here.
It's just a t...statement let's submit this against the pool and see what happens.
So,...was
...running this job now so this job is basically running in a cloud service that you
have provision against your subscription and you manage yourself at this point but,
it's tightly integrated with the portals as soon as you go through the provisioning experience for
these cloud services then they basically snap to the elastic database
pools if you have shell so let's look at the job
analysis what has happened to it this is the one we just created and you can see
...already completed and you see that and ran successfully against all
of these databases now since we have global query we can actually
or lasting database query we can actually check this out and see that's
...and the job has really run so let's run this...statement again.
And, see what countries we have.
And, yes, very much indeed.
...are...so, the counts the...databases...have that's the kind of
various that's countries for the ola databases all thirty-two databases
that landed and with that change premium awesome
okay so with that let me jump back to that slide that you
...which is this one just to
illustrate the capability that we just have seen basically elastic database jobs rolling out that's
t sequel statement across your database pool.
Okay.
So, with that.
One hundred back to...was just wrap up here ...let's just summarize and,
remind ourselves key things so obviously we're talking about as you're single database
are global databases a service and you've seen today
...to target a predictable workloads and then most specifically
and interestingly today we've been seeing and, talking about this use of a
support for unpredictable workloads with our elastic and elastic database
model has the use of elastic databases in a lasting database pools
...pooling story and throughout this thing to remind ourselves is that in a
sense nothing's changed about the underlying database databases still sequel
databases that can fully compatible with the sql sequel server twenty
fourteen databases at the same...execute...you can use the same tools the same
...experience the same connection management technologies
platforms and then this simple self-service management and
...only...various things in the management...backed
at every stage by a programmable apis partial,
come on, let's as well as the portal operations so that's the that's the platform
that's the story thank you very much...attention this afternoon.
We'd love to do is invite you to try this out to get
to get started those of you building sas applications to build them on this platform to
exploit this technology and, ...triad these new elastic features here that
we've been we've been talking about and we're happy to take questions like...a as a gang of people
...hunched.
And,...the forget some resources here
...so you can connect to these here to look,
through these and then please I said ...evaluation
for the session we love to hear what you think about this...love to hear of here of course about what you think about the...